Bangalore India (+91) 7073069375 catchyash007@gmail.com H&J

Yash Kumar

Summary

Security Researcher involved in cyber security from more than 3 years (~2 years in corporate). Focus towards Low level security work, including Software Security, Reverse engineering, Malware analysis, Windows Internals and Application and Network Penetration Testing.

Relevant Skills

Reverse Engineering and Malware Analysis

- Disassembling and analysing binaries in Windows/Linux
- Knowledge of windows internals and PE file formats
- Dynamic and Static analysis of malwares
- Software Exploitation research

Penetration Testing

- Network Penetration Testing
- Web, APIs, Thick Client Application security assessment

Experience

Société Générale, Bangalore — Security Analyst

June 2019 - PRESENT

Penetration Testing of Web Applications, Infrastructure, API and Thick Client Applications.

ArcelorMittal, Kazakhstan — Network Engineering Intern

June 2018 - July 2018

Network Infrastructure Implementation and Penetration Testing.

Education

```
LNM IIT, Jaipur — CCE
July 2015 - Aug 2019
```

Communication and Computing Engineering,

Bachelors in Technology.

Technical competence

- Reverse Engineering
- Intel x86/_64 asm
- Security Assessment
- Windows/Linux Exploitation
- Programming(Python,C)
- Computer Networking
- IoT/IoT Security
- Embedded System
- Socket Programming
- Binary Debugging
- Cryptography
- Malware Analysis(SA,DA)
- Windows API programming(c++)

Tools & Frameworks

Network Penetration Testing - Wireshark, Metasploit, Nmap, Nessus

Application Security Assessment - Burp Suite, ZAP, Nikto

Reverse Engineering - IDA, Windbg, x64 dbg, ollydbg, GDB

Dynamic Analysis - Sysinternal Suite, PEstudio, CFF exp

Projects & Achievements

- Beta Tester(OpenSecurityTraining) Working with Xeno Kovah for enhancing courses on x86 assembly and exploitation
- **IOT Security** API implementation of Elgamal Encryption using Elliptic Curve Cryptography in Python.
- Internet Of Things Alarming System.
- Windows API Programming A tool for analysing PE headers.
- Cryptography RSA Implementation in Python.
- All India Rank 5 Hackathon conducted by Societe Generale(bangalore)

Hobbies

- Cycling
- Vlogging/Blogging
- Travelling
- Reading History/Geography
- Wrestling and Brazilian Jiu-Jitsu